Abdoulage SAYOUTI SOULEYMANE

R&D Artificial Intelligence Engineer at Aiway

Portfolio https://abdoulaye-sayouti.github.io/

Profil

Driven Al engineer with 2+ years' experience building NLP models and working on 3D data processing. Has a strong background in software development and telecommunications. Fluent in French and English; I also contribute to Open Source initiatives within the AI community.

Work Experience & Projects

2022-10 Aiway, Aix-en-Provence

Present R&D Artificial Intelligence Engineer

- · Audit of models developed in the dental field in order to identify, correct and improve shortcomings in the process of data preparation, training and evaluation of these
- Development of a python library for adapting planned digital building models (BIM IFC) to reflect the as-built state of the structure.
- Technologies: Python, Open3D, PyTorch3D, IfcOpenShell, BIMcollab ZOOM, MeshLab, Scikit-Learn & GitLab

2021-06 Enedis Al Lab, Marseille

2022-09 Artificial Intelligence Engineer Apprentice

- Text and time series data processing.
- Technology watch, development of various models (text classification, NER, text generation and auto-completion), then deployment of these models in production.
- Technologies: Python, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, RegEx, CamemBERT, BARThez, PostgreSQL, Flask, Docker, CodeCarbon & GitLab

2020-05 Infineon Technologies Padova, Italy

2020-09 Data Analyst Intern

- Design and development of a dashboard for real-time visualization and validation of the company's software, firmware and hardware development processes, in compliance with ISO 26262 "Road vehicles - Functional safety" and Automotive SPICE standards.
- Technologies: Python, MySQL, Logstash, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Balsamiq Wireframe, Jenkins.

2021-03 School projects

2021-06 Hadoop & Rasa Open Source

- Development of a Voice Chatbot and interfacing with Pepper and NAO robots using the Rasa Open Source framework and Coregraphe Suite.
- Distributed implementation of the K-means clustering algorithm using Hadoop's MapReduce parallel programming paradigm.

Education

2020-10 Center for Education and Research in Computer Science (CERI)

- 2022-06 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence, Avignon University
- 2019-09 University of Padova, Italy
- 2020-09 ERASMUS + M.Sc in ICT for Internet and Multimedia
- 2017-09 Higher School of Communication of Tunis, University of Carthage
- **2020-09** Engineer in Telecommunications
- National School of Electronics and Telecoms, University of Sfax 2016-09
- 2017-06 1st year M.Sc in Information and Communications Technology

2013-09 Faculty of Sciences of Gabes, University of Gabes

2016-06 B.Sc in Computer Science

Paper & Certifications

HAPe: Optimizing Customer Relation by Automatic Task Distribution using Constrained 2023-08 Optimization and Natural Language Processing (CIRED 2023 - Enedis)

Mathematics For Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera) 2020-11

2019-11 Neural Network and Deep Learning (Coursera)

2019-05 98-369:MTA: Cloud Fundamentals (Microsoft)

Personal Info



Marseille, France



(+33) 7 49 82 75 89



abdoulaye.sayoutisouley mane@gmail.com



https://github.com/ Abdoulaye-Sayouti



https://www.linkedin.com/ in/sayouti-souleymaneabdoulave/

Industries

- · Telecommunications.
- Electricity.
- Building information modeling (BIM).
- Dental.
- Semiconductor.

Skills

Machine Learning & Deep Learning

Natural Language Processing

3D data processing

MLOps, Docker & GitLab

Python & Scikit-Learn

PyTorch & TensorFlow

Transformers & RegEx

Hadoop & Talend

lacktriangle

Data Visualization, Tableau & ELK Stack

PostgreSQL & AWS

C, C++ & Java

Linux/Unix & Matlab

••••

JavaScript, NodeJs, Flask & PHP



Languages

French

English (B2)